Kahler, Erich von; Papers ger048
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Erich von Kahler Papers
1905-1977
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger048
13 cubic ft.
This collection contains diaries, 1906-1913; correspondence; corrected manuscripts of literary works by Hermann Broch, Golo Mann, and others, 1945-1970; lecture notes on philosophy of history; and contemporary politics for lectures given in Germany and the United States.
Collection X
Biographical / Historical
Erich Von Kahler was born on October 14, 1885 in Prague. Kahler studied at the University of Munich, the University of Berlin, the University of Heidelberg, and the University of Freiburg. Kahler received his doctorate from the University of Vienna in 1911. He was stripped of his German citizenship in 1933 because he was Jewish. Kahler eventually emigrated to the United States in 1938. He became a U.S. citizen in 1944.
Kahler taught at a variety of universities in the United States including The New School, Black Mountain College, Cornell University, and Princeton University. Kahler was a member of the Institute for Advanced Study and wrote many books on politics, technology, and science. Kahler was married to Josephine Sobotka, and later to Alice (Lili) Loewy. Kahler died on June 28, 1970, in Princeton, New Jersey and was survived by his wife and stepdaughter.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains diaries, 1906-1913; correspondence in German and English with Hans Bethe, Richard BeerHofmann, Jacob Bronowski, Albert Einstein, Elizabeth Mann Borgese, Erich Fromm, Herbert Marcuse, J. Robert Oppenheimer, Kurt Wolff, and others, 1923-1970. This collection also includes corrected manuscripts of literary works by Hermann Broch, Golo Mann, and others, 1945-1970, lecture notes on philosophy of history, Jewish history, German literature, and contemporary politics for lectures given in Germany and the United States and for courses at Black Mountain College and Ohio State University, 1915-1968.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eight general series based upon an earlier arrangement.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This majority of the collection was donated by Alice Loewy Kahler in the late 1970s with a small amount of material donated by Janit Roberts in 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the processed material in boxes 1-10 of this collection is unrestricted. Access to the unprocessed material in the remaining portion of the collection is restricted. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Kahler, Erich, 1885-1970; Correspondence; Diaries.; Manuscripts.; Lecture notes; Jews -- Germany -- Berlin..; Exiles -- Germany.
- Correspondence, 1923-1970; 1
  - A - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adam, Fredrich, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alewyn, Nelly, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alewyn, Richard, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anders, Gunther, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aschaffenburg, Karl, 1951; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B - Miscellaneous Coresspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bab, Julius, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Barford, Niels, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baxter, Charles, 1934-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beer - Hofmann (Lens), Mirjam, 1923-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Beer - Hofmann, Naemah, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beer - Hofmann, Richard, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Benton, Jose, Antonio, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Berendsohn, Walter, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Berrnann - Fischer, Gottfried, 1937-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bernhardt, Kate, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bethe, Hans A., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bethe, Rose (Mrs. Hans A), 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Block, Victor, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Blum, Emil, Undated; 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Blumenfeld, Hans (City Planning Comission), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bohm, David, 1967; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Borgese, Elisabeth Mann, 1942-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Borgese, G. A., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Borries, Achim Von, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bothmer, Bernhard Von, 1944; 1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Boyle, Kay, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brantl, George (Braziller), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Braun, Nancy, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brentano, Bernard Von, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brinckman, Elsa, 1936-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brinckmann, Richard, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Broch, Herman, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bruning, Heinrich, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Burckhardt, S., 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - C - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Canetti, Elias, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cohn, Fritz, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Collin, Ernst, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Collin, G. Pohl, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Curtius, Klaus, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Curtius, Ludwig, 1948; 1949 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - D - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - David, Claude, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dehn, Georg (Jorge), 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Domin, Hilde, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Dreier, Theodore, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - E - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Eckelberry, R.H. (Journal of Higher Education), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Editor of the New York Times, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1943; 1950 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Einstein, Alfred, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Einstein, Margot, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Elliot, Bob and Mary, 1967; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Elper, Herman, 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Erffa, Martha Agnes Frfr. V., 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Eulenberg, Adelhied, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Exner, Richard, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - F - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Falk, Richard, 1960; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Ricke, Ludwig Von, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Fles, Barthold, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Franck, James, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Frank, Joseph, 1967; Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Fried, Erich, Undated; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Fried, John, 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Frisch, Ephraim, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Frisch, Irma, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Fromm, Erich, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - G - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Gauss, Christian, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - George, Stefan, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Ginsberg, Ernst, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Glaser, Curt, 1939-1940; 1949 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Glatzer, Nahum Norbert, 1964; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Goldsmith, Ulrich, 1950; 1951 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Goldstein, Kurt, Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Gothein, Werner, 1938-1960 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Greenberg, Clement, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Grunewald, Max, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Guedalla, Roger, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Guillen, Claudio, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Guillen, Jorge, 1948; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - H - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Haas, Willy, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Hamburger, Max, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Hamburger, Michael, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Hartmann, Heinz, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Hecht, Maria, 1933; 1960; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Herzog, Anna, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Hiller, Robert L., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Hillmann, Heidi and Mickey, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Hirsch, Rudolf, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Hosle, Johannes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Ilma, Viola, Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - J - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Jacob, Heinrich Eduard, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Jechouda, Josue, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Jessner, Lucie, 1949-1951; 1960 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Johann, Ernst, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1943; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Jonas, Klaus, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - K - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Kahler Family Correspondence, 1939-1967 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Kahler, Antoinette, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Kalser, E., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Kasack, Hermann, 1954; 1957 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Kaskell, Joseph, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Kauder, Hugo and Helene, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Kesten, Hermann, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Kiel, Anna, Undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Kisch, Guido, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Koebner, Thomas, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Kraus, Gerry, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Krieger, Arnold, 1952; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Kuepper, Helmut, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Kupper, Ursula, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - L - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Landauer, Richard, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Lange, Victor, 1947-1969 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Lederer, Gertrude, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Lewin, Wera, 1957; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Liebert, Arthur, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Lion, Ferdinand, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Loewenthal, Rudolf, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Lowinsky, Edward, 1945-1960 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Luschnat, David, 1951; 1955 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Lutz, A., 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - M - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Maass, Joachim, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Mainland, W.F., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Mann, Golo, 1940; 1944 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Mann, Klaus, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Marcusy, Lela, Undated (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Marcusy, Lotte, Undated (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - May, Rollo, 1959; 1960 (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - McCormick, Ken, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Meisel, James H., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Merwin, Bill, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Mommsen, Theodor, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Monas, Sidney, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Moos, Walter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar, Undated (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Morrison, Phil, 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Mauumiller - Seidel, Walter, 1954-1956; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Musil, Robert, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Robert - Musil - Archiv, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - N, O - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Natanson, Maurice, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - Newton, Caroline, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Nikisch, Martin, 1967; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Norden, Ruth, 1951; Undated (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Oprecht, Emmie, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Osterie, Heinz D., 1964; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 157)
  - P - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 158)
  - Paakkanen, Eila, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 159)
  - Paetel, Karl O., 1945; 1949; Undated (Box 1, Folder 160)
  - Pannwitz, Rudolf, 1936-1938; 1946 (Box 1, Folder 161)
  - Panofsky, Erwin, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 162)
  - Pauli, Wolfgang (and Franoa), 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 163)
  - Peacock, R., 1959; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 164)
  - Harvey, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 165)
  - Phillips, John, 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 166)
  - Picard, Michael, 1940-1966 (Box 1, Folder 167)
  - Plessner, Alexander, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 168)
  - Podewils, Clemens, 1964; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 169)
  - Polak, Ernst, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 170)
  - Politzer, Heinz, 1948; 1951 (Box 1, Folder 171)
  - Preetorius, Emil, Undated (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - R - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 173)
  - Reed, Herbert, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 174)
  - Reichmann, Maria, 1940-1956; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 175)
  - Reif (Rowe), Naomi and Paula, 1954-1967 (Box 1, Folder 176)
  - Reinhardt, Delia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 177)
  - Richter, Fridel (Mrs. Hans Werner), 1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 178)
  - Richter, Hans Wener, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 179)
  - Rosenfeild, Hans, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 180)
  - Ruben, Margot, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 181)
  - Rukser, Udo, 1944-1966 (Box 1, Folder 182)
  - S - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 183)
  - Sahl, Hans, 1941; 1944; 1952 (Box 1, Folder 184)
  - Saiko, George, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 185)
  - Salin, Edgar, 1964-1966; 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 186)
  - Salz, Beate, 1946-1966 (Box 1, Folder 187)
  - Salz, Soscha, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 188)
  - Sartorius, Klara, 1939-1948 (Box 1, Folder 189)
  - Sauerlander, Wolfgang, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 190)
  - Schampenberg (Wellmann), Margot, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 191)
  - Schiffer, Walter and Helene, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 192)
  - Schirokauer, Arno, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 193)
  - Schlosser, Manfred (Agora Verlag), 1942-1965 (Box 1, Folder 194)
  - Schnitzler, Heinrich, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 195)
  - Schnitzler, Olga, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 196)
  - Scholem, Gerhard, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 197)
  - Schowiese, Ernst, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 198)
  - Meyer, Hemann R., Undated (Box 1, Folder 199)
  - Schroers, Rolf, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Schwarzchild, Leopold (Das Neue Tage - Buch), 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Schwerin, Christoph, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Seelig, Carl, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Seidenberg, Roderick, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Seidlin, Oskar, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Serkinm Rudolf, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Session, Roger, 1945; 1947-1948; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sewell, Elzabeth, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shahn, Bernarda, 1950; 1956; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Snyder, Sarah, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sobotka, Hans, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sobotka, Valentin and Franya, 1940-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Speier, Hans, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sperling, Bob, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stafford, Jack, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Steiner, George, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Steiner, Herbert, 1940-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sterba, Verena and Richard, 1943; 1949-1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stern, Fritz, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sternfeld, Willhelm, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stillmann, Ernst, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Straus, Erwin, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sulger, Kurt Armand, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Szekely, Bustav, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - T, V - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Taylor, Harold, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Theile, Albert, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Trebitsch, Siegfried, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ullmann, Regina, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1948-1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Urzidil, Johannes, 1951; 1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - V, W - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Van Fossen, Theodore, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Vietta, Egon, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Vordtriede, Werner, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Waard, Bede, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Waehner, Trude, 1939-1955 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Waldinger, Ernst, 1952-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Walter, Bruno, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Walters, Dean Everett, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Weber, Dr. Kahler's last letter, 1970 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Wedekind, Kadidja, 1948-1949; 1957 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Weigard, Herman J., 1946-1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Weisinger, Herbert, 1950-1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Weitz, Morris, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Welt, Elizabeth, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Weltsch, Robert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Wendt, H., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Wetzddt, Lili, 1947-1968 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Winston Richard, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Winter, Anne, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Wolff, Eleanor, 1940-1966 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Wolff, Kurt and Helene, Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Wolf, Helene, 1952-1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1950-1967 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Wonderly, Wayne, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Worringer, Marta and Wilheim, 1947-1965 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Wyatt, Frederick, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - X, Y, Z - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Zimmer, Christiane, Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Zoff, Otto, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Zuckerkandl, Gertrud, Undated; 1965 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Zuckerkandl, Mimi, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Zuckerkandl, Victor, 1937-1965 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Zuckmayer, Carl, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - American Scholar, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Commentary, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Cornell University Press, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - S. Fischer Verlag, 1948-1968 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Georg Bondi Verlag Receipts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Goverts Verlag, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jonathan Cape Ltd., Publishers, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Kooehler Verlag, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Kohlhammer Verlag (Oskar Ruhle), 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Menorah: School, Journal, Club, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Merkur (Hans Paeschke), 1948-1968 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Pantheon Books. Finacial Statements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Princeton Unviersity Press (Miriam Brokaw), 1955; 1961 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Rowohlt Verlag, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, 1940-1957 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Social Research, 1940-1944 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Twice A Year, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence with Publishers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - American Committee for Cultral Freedom, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - "Articles" Miscellaneous Correspondence Concerning Article Submitted, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - "Besprechungen" Correspondence conceming Reviews by Kahler, Undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - "Briege aus Europa" Transcripts of L., Undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - College of the City of New York, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Deutsche Akademie fur Sprache and Dichtung, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Fulbright fellowship, University of Manchester, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Jewish Organizations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - John Siman Suggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - "Konferenzen - Seminare", Undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - N.Y.S. Association of European Historians, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Recommendations, Undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Students. Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Teaching Positions, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Translations. Correspondence Concerning Translations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Universities and Institutes Correspondence (Lecture Engagements), 1943-1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - World Federalists, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 70th Birthday Congratulations, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ca. 175 Condolence L. and Cards to Lily Kahler, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kahler, Alice Loewy Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Quotations (Many From Burckhardt) Inotations, etc., Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Diaries and Notebooks, 1905-1923; 2
  - Diaries: Okt. 1906 - 14 Feb. 1907, 1906-1907 (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    A. 62p. Numerous inserted note pages and cl.
  - Diaries: Jan. 1910 - M채rz 1911, 1910-1911 (Box 3)
    A. 162p.
  - Diaries: April 2, 1911 - Sept. 21, 1911 (Box 3)
    A. 91p. Ptc. inserted.
  - Diaries: Nov. 22, 1912 - Jan. 20, 1913, 1912-1913 (Box 3)
    A. 82p. Inserted: 8 Ptc.
  - Diaries: 7 Mai 1913 - 10 Mai 1913 (Box 3)
    A. 3p. Inserted notes. A. 4p.
  - Notebooks: "Sonette 1905/06", 1905-1906 (Box 3)
    Pergament notebook. A. 8p. + 3p. inserts.
  - Notebooks: "Die reinen Zeichen. Feuer unter dem Boden, 1905-1908 (Box 3)
    Poems and prose excerpts. A. 22p. + 2p. inserts.
  - Notebooks: "Kulturgeographie (Geistesgeographie). Geschichte des Menschen." Notebook, with the comment "Begonnen 1910" (Box 3)
    A. 144p. Inserts and cl 19P.
  - Notebooks: "Die Methoden der geistigen Weltbeherrschung. (Die Arten der geistigen Weltheherrschung)." With the comment: "Begonnen Juni 1911"
    A. 5p.
  - Notebooks: "Gestern, Heut und Morgen." With the comment: "Begonnen 1912" (Box 3)
    A.14p.
  - Notebooks: "Grund-S채tze; (Plan Fr체hjahr; 1912)." With the comment: "Begonnen, Februar 1916" (Box 3)
    A. 2p. Inserted notes. A. 10P.
  - Notebooks: "Florenz 1914" (Box 3)
    A. 22p. Inserted notes. A. 4p.
  - Notebooks: Black composition notebook with drafts of important correspondence, including Friedrich Gundolf, Kurt Hildebrandt, 1920-1923 (Box 3)
    circa 100p. plus inserts.
  - Notebooks: "German Reich and Nazi Total State", Undated (Box 3)
    Several inserted p.
  - Notebooks: "G체ltige; Gedicht - Correcturen", Undated (Box 3)
    1 p. in notebook. A. Inserts. A. 5P.
  - Notebooks: "Johannsen. Experimentelle Grundlagen d. Descendenzlehre etc.", Undated (Box 3)
    A. 18p.
  - Notebooks: Note pad in floral folder, Undated (Box 3)
  - Notebooks: "Protestantism, Calvin and Luther", Undated (Box 3)
  - Notebooks: Quotations (many from Burckhardt), notations, etc., Undated (Box 3)
    Notations, etc. Loose p. T. 120p.
  - Notebooks: Quotations, notations, Undated (Box 3)
    cl. Loose p. T. and A. circa 250p.
- Manuscripts by Kahler, 1907-1970; 3
  - Short Autobiographical Statement, for "Twice a Year", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Adbankung des Sozialismus und Niedergang des Kapitalismus", Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Alte Notizen Zur Philosophie und wiseenschaft.", 1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Semitism Lecture Notes. Columbia University, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Art and History" English Version. T., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "The Articles of Two Eminent Zionist Leaders", Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Banking and Mining." T., Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Bilingualism." German Version., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Bilingualism and the Problems of Translation", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bollingen Foundation proposal: "Outline of the Project: Evolution and Transformation of Human Consclaisness", 1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bollingen Foundation - Application, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Broch [Hermann] Lecture. Various Versions, 1958 April (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hermann Broch Lecture - Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Broch Lecture for Osterreichische Rundfunk - Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Statement about Broch, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Collective Individualists." T., Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "The Common Enemy.", 1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "The Concept of Simultanelty Among Austro - Hungarian Thinkers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Crisis of the Individual", 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Crisis of the Individual" - Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Culture" - Materials for Course, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "Culture" Course notes. Kahler Seminar, Chio State University, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Culture II" Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Culture III", Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Culture, and Evolution", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Culture and Evolution"- Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Debate on Freudianism" Wayne State University, 1961 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Democracy Today and Tomorrow" Pe. of T., 1965 December 2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "Denkschirift zur Begrundung einer akademischen Brudderschaft (Orden, Cpngregation), Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - "Doctor Faustus from Adam to Sartre." T., Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - "Einstein the Man. (on 75th Birthday)", Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - "The Epochal Innovations in Hermann Broch's Narrative", Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Ford Foundation Proposal T., Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "Foreign Policy Today" Dated Aspen, 1950 August 12 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Form and Entformung" A., Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - "Form and Entformung" -Mss., 1940 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Form und Entformung - Note, Materials, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Forms and Features of Anti - Judaism" T., 1940 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Forms and Features of Anit - Judaism" - Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)